feel like the lifestyle of having the
flexibility of bug bounty as well has
bred some really unexpected but cool
opportunities which I just never would
have guessed could have happened.
>> Best part of acting when you can just
you know critical think
[Music]
All
right, hackers. We all know the value of
a good misconfiguration, right? That's
often how we're popping bugs and bug
bounties. Well, unfortunately, Threat
Locker also knows about it, which is why
they built DAC, defense against
configurations. DAX scans all of the
enterprise machines in your network for
misconfigurations, ranks them by
severity, and then shows them in nice
graphics in a portal. It even emails
your team weekly with updates so nothing
slips through the cracks. And the best
part about DAC in my opinion is that it
actually maps all these
misconfigurations onto security
frameworks and it also shows you how to
fix them. That way when you need ammo
with leadership or with it, you can
point to real specific compliance gaps
um and get actionable steps. Anyway,
check out Threat Locker DAC. It's an
awesome way to stay ahead of these
issues that we as attackers love. All
right, let's go back to the show.
All righty. Sup hackers. We got the this
week in bug bounty segment and I guess
I'll start this week off actually with a
shout out to the Epic Games team for an
amazing live hacking event in Sweden
this past week. I had a blast. So much
fun and currently in first place got to
say, you know, not a bad time for me.
Um, but yeah, really the team was
excellent there and definitely wanted to
give them a shout out because uh that
was a S tier event and the way that they
interacted with the hackers,
collaborated, escalated bugs,
phenomenal. Phenomenal. You rarely see
an experience like that uh that that
detailed at a live hacking event where
they really hit checked every box. So
anyway, I'm I'm kind of glowing as you
guys can tell from a really awesome week
of hacking. Um, damn, this is such a
great job, guys. We really have the most
amazing job. Um, all right. So, let's
let's get into the content for this week
for the this week in Bug Bounty. Um,
first up, we've got a article by Yes, We
Hack. Once again, just releasing these
ultimate guides on various bug classes.
Really digging this series. It's great
for getting like in-depth um analysis of
your methodology for uh various bug
class. And this week is race conditions.
Now, race conditions is something I
don't actually do very much of because
I'm using Kaido and we don't have a
bunch of tooling right now for race
conditions. But um this uh this blog
outlines the different kind of attacks
you can do with uh HP 1.1 last bite
synchronization attacks and HTP2 uh
single packet race condition attacks um
which we've talked about a lot in the
pod. Really awesome stuff here. So check
it out if you're interested in um sort
of brushing up on uh race condition
vulnerabilities.
Um also crazy uh from Yes We Hack. The
dojo just got a total faceelift guys. So
check this out. Look at if you for those
on on YouTube, check out my screen right
now. Um, super beautiful design here.
And uh, as always, Yes, We Hack is
running awesome challenges on
dojo-ywhack.com.
This this month's is uh, Chain Fection,
which looks like some file upload
vulnerabilities happening here. So,
always good to check that out if you
guys are looking to sharpen your skills.
And what a lot of people don't know is
when you solve these dojo challenges,
you get um, you get points in invites on
Yes, We Hack. So, pretty awesome. All
right, last but not least, guys, uh I
told you a couple weeks ago that Bug
Crowd, specifically Santara, uh was
looking for people to come and do PR
opportunities, right? Well, for those of
you that are watching the screen right
now, you are looking at my boy GM me
Brandon uh on TV in Britain uh via those
opportunities with Bug Crowd. So,
definitely if you're a top skill hacker,
um shoot an email, say, "Hey, I'm open
to PR opportunities." and you might end
up on TV like Brandon did um in this
scenario. So anyway, just wanted to
shoot that out. If you guys are
interested in seeing the segment, we'll
link it in the description. And with
that, we'll jump right into the show.
Let's go.
>> Hey. Hey. What's up, guys? I am here
with Brandon Gret. Uh you may remember
him from a few months ago. Did you say
it was like seven or eight months ago?
>> I think it was around about that time.
It was during the my first LH actually
just after.
>> Nice. And at that time you had been
hacking for like a year. Had doing been
doing bug bunny for about a year.
>> Um at the time of the last interview it
had only been eight or nine months. So
in bug bounty specifically. So I was
still in that very rich learning
process. First LH um coming to terms
with everything and yeah it's been a
crazy ride since then.
>> Sweet. Yeah. And um so Justin and you
obviously like knew each other back then
and then you kind of have been doing
hacker notes through the through this
year. But what what the audience
probably doesn't know is that you and I
have done a bunch of hacking together
this year on on uh a mix of AI products
and bug bounty programs and even a pin
test here or there. So uh this guy is is
uh you know what I would consider you
know a top tier kind of AI security
hacker as well. Um, and we'll we'll talk
a little about that later in the
episode, but first, yeah, I wanted to
hear, you know, what uh what you've been
up to for this year. How has going
full-time been? You know, what's it
looked like?
Yeah, full-time. As I said, it's been a
bit of a journey. And I feel like the
lifestyle of having the flexibility of
Bug Bounty as well has bred some really
unexpected but cool opportunities which
I just never would have guessed could
have happened without having the
flexibility of doing Bug Bounty. Um, so
I've been full-time since January. So,
what is that? 8 months, 8 months, 9
months. Um, I've participated in a few
more in-person events since then. Um,
I've taken home awards from Inerson
events um, a few times which has been
really nice. Um, and yeah, it's just
been such a good journey and I'm very
grateful for the community and being
able to do it really,
>> dude. Yeah, I had even thought about the
fact that we went full-time in the same
month.
>> That's awesome. We actually did. And
that was when do you remember the
hackbot that we absolutely wrecked and
dropped a crit and a high. And
>> yeah,
>> that was like the I feel like that was
like the real gateway. That was
literally within the first week or two
of me going full-time. I feel like that
was the gateway for like the AI hacking
when I was like, "Right, this is really
something I'm I'm going to go down now."
>> Yeah. contributed to a bunch of the
findings and invites through this year
and how all that shook out.
>> Yeah. And uh on the side of that as
well, some other things that have
happened, I unexpectedly started a
company which was a very natural
byproduct of a lot of the outreach I was
getting. Um so there's been a lot of
lessons learned there as well.
>> Yeah. Sorry, actually I meant to say
something a second ago. I was going to
say um like that flexibility uh that
comes with being a full-time hunter. I
think really does allow people like you
and I to like say yes to more things. I
think whenever you have a full-time job
and then you're doing bug bounty on the
side, the margin that we have in our
lives for things that are outside of,
you know, that salary work and and you
know those like precious bug bounty
hours in the evenings or whatever is
like pretty small, especially if you
have a family or lots of other
obligations. And um and so yeah,
whenever you said that earlier, I was
like, man, that's so true. Like that's
been one huge upside of this year is
just the opportunity to say yes to more
things because you don't have like a
40hour a week job kind of sitting there
all the time. And I know um you know a
lot of people I think who are full-time
hunters often talk about that freedom of
flexibility, freedom of schedule, being
able to work from anywhere. And man, um
I think before I went full-time, I I I
really thought more about that free time
that I would be able to have like for my
family or for hobbies, but I didn't
think about all the opportunities that
it lets you say yes to for professional
work that you can just kind of swap some
of that time with, right? So instead of
doing 100% bug biting hours, it's like,
oh yeah, I can do 30% of my time on
Pinterest and 20% of time on this side
project that could blow up. And you
know, for me personally, like you know,
5% of my time on helping advise
companies that may eventually be like a
second retirement, right? It's like it
allows you to say yes to all these
things you couldn't say yes to before.
>> 100%. And I think it's important as
well, I've been speaking to a lot of
hackers about this. Um, hackus comes to
mind more recently, but when you are a
certain tier of bug bounty hunter, and I
need to thank Justin for giving me some
advice on this, you really need to weigh
up opportunities and opportunity cost as
well and what that means for you as a
hunter. So say if you're in an LHE scene
and you are thinking about starting a
company or you are thinking about a side
project uh half reality is and again it
depends on the country because of
different obligations things like that
but you probably will take a bit of a
hit initially in your income and you
have to be prepared and ready for that.
Um, and it's one of the one of the
things I would like to point out if if
you are thinking about doing that is to
be very real about what you can make and
what sort of income you can generate.
>> Um, and equally aside from the income,
what actually fills your cup rather than
take from it, right? Like what what
works for you. And I think for me again
another completely unexpected byproduct
of having the the freedom from bug
bounty is finding out I actually really
like doing like conferences and talks.
I've done a lot this year and that has
had another impact of generating so many
opportunities for me for my company and
doing some really good networking. So I
would say definitely exercise caution
when you are looking at some of these
opportunities like even me and you have
spoken about one of your recent
engagements when there's a little bit of
push back on your side which actually
worked out really well for you but
definitely be honest with yourself and
weigh up okay this is what I can
generate there's going to be a bit of
hidden income if you do think about
going down that route.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I loved what you said
there about like um kind of like
learning more about yourself. Like the
fact that you learned that you enjoy
doing speaking and stuff. I I knew that
I disliked like um meetings and maybe
what's the best way to say this? Like
accountability from work. Like I've
always hated like logging time for
example. But I've realized that even
more like I was doing a pin test and
like an AI security pin test recently
and I got an email uh from one of the
one of the um customers or like one of
the people who work at the customers
like the head of security and he was
like yeah if you don't mind just shoot
me over like you know two sentences at
the end of the day about like you know
like what you were like hacking on or
working on that day for us or like would
you mind to do that? And my initial
inclination was like no I won't do that.
Like I don't I don't have to do that.
I'm not going to do that. Um, but
obviously that wouldn't have been like
the most tactful way to say that. And
so, uh, luckily I I posted my draft
email in a Discord channel and Shubs and
ZLZ were kind enough to be like, you
shouldn't say that that way. You should
say it like this. And we ended up
rewarding it as like, uh, hey, my normal
flow is to stay in a flow state. I I
take notes about what I'm doing. And we
can talk about that like the at the end
of the week meeting. And, uh, they were
like, yeah, yeah, sure. Just, you know,
do it your way. Do it do it the way you
normally do it. And so that was like a
really tactful way to not have to deal
with that. But I do think like um yeah,
just like a huge upside that we talked
about with Bug Bounty that really was
present in that moment was the fact that
you don't have any you have no boss, you
know? Um and and when you're even if
you're solo freelance and you're doing
an engagement, you do have a boss,
right? They hired you, they're paying
you, they kind of have the right to ask
things of you. And so uh for me, you
know, that kind of pounded home and and
honestly, the the the pin test that I
handed off to you is kind of the same
way. I just got a weird vibe from uh one
of the people who were going to hire me
for a pin test and I handed it off to
you and we ended up tacting it later and
it was fantastic. But um but yeah, I
love that you do get a little bit more
of like self introspection and
exploration when it comes to being on
your own. You know, you really do kind
of it's more visceral what you like and
don't like because you can say no to
slightly more.
>> Exactly that. Exactly that. And what I
will say as well, I think a thing that
isn't really thought about is when you
are starting these ventures and you are
exploring other opportunities. More
often than not, it's a very very
different skill set than the one you
used to bug bounty hunting, right? The
reason why bug bounty is so cool is
because you get to spend so much time on
the cool stuff that you really like. And
okay, yes, there are some caveats with
triage and company politics sometimes
when things get downgraded or whatever,
but
that is that pales in the comparison to
some of the other stuff you have to do.
Like take your example of logging time
sheets. I'd rather pull my own teeth out
than have to do that again. I just not
something I want to do. Mhm.
>> So
ultimately I would say yeah full-time Bi
has been great and it's gave me so many
opportunities but there has been a
reality of some learning where you do
realize that okay maybe I shouldn't have
said yes to that or maybe I should have
worded that a little bit differently
because until you try something else I
don't think you realize how good the bug
bounty lifestyle really is. um just with
that freedom.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Sweet, dude. Well, I'm glad
that's going super well. Did you want to
mention uh your uh pentest company you
started?
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, Mr. M u r t a sec um is
a pentest company. We've been running
for I would say since February time
unofficially and then we properly
launched the site 3 months ago to
capitalize on all the leads that were
coming inbound and things like that. And
yeah, we've really hammer down on web
applications, AI, and APIs. We have a
small service offering because that's
what myself and the researchers we work
with like to look at. And yeah, it's
honestly been so good to be able to have
the opportunity to work with some of the
cooler customers in the AI space, people
that are doing really cutting edge
things, and also just share the love and
work with my friends as well. It's been
really good.
>> That's one of the coolest things is
being able to hire your friends to work
with you, right?
>> Absolutely. uh and just put money in
their pocket, too. Like I hired Exili uh
for this engagement over the summer and
it was like, you know, great pay for him
and it was fun to work together and
honestly I feel like I get more done,
stay more focused when I have friends
that I'm working with, you know.
>> Absolutely. It's uh it gives you that
bit more motivation and accountability
as well, I think.
>> Yeah. Sweet, dude. Well, uh I know
Justin would be uh whipping our backs
with uh you know, staying not again not
being technical enough. So, we're going
to we're going to dive into um some
notes. Um Brandon and I both like we
were looking at some ABSC stuff and then
we've got a bunch of AI research because
uh I already cover enough AI stuff in
general. We'll stick the AI stuff at the
end though it is some like really high
quality good stuff. But um Brandon
brought brought two things to the table
here about um you know just traditional
apps that I think is really useful. Um
we can dive straight into those if you
want to mention the first one.
>> Yeah, sure. So the first one I got on
the list is from Portfiger. Let me share
my screen actually.
>> Yeah, I had no idea they had released
this. So this is this is really cool.
will probably have me um uh double
fisting proxies
anytime I need to look at websockets.
>> That is exactly where I'm at and it's
not a nice setup. I can trust you. Um
but websocket turbo intruder um very
very nice. I did briefly have a play
around with it and I feel like it's
another one of the Portswiger
specialtities where they address a
problem that everyone else is a bit
scared of because of the complexity and
trying to address that problem and
essentially they made some updates to it
with some really nice quality of life
things as well um just around testing
websockets. can be such a pain
sometimes, especially if you are trying
to exploit some of the more exotic bugs.
But just getting a general handle
>> with it has been incredibly painful on
some targets. So, this is a very very
welcome addition. Now, one of the cool
things that they did, um, look, where is
it? You've got some filtering in there,
the automated testing part, but the
thing I did want to shout out, uh, where
is it?
Ah this was one of them. So whilst they
were using their tool for testing a
websockets implementation they found
websockets ping of death um which was
completely unexpected
>> and it was a denial of service in a Java
websocket implementation. Um, and
essentially using the turbo engine, they
can send malformed websocket frames
which goes outside of the spec that it
was expecting. And lo and behold, it
resulted in an out of memory crash. And
uh, they actually released the ping of
death example.py if you did want to use
it if you do come across some of the
Java implementations of websockets.
>> I love it whenever, you know, uh, any
write up includes a PD like that. even
more so in like nowadays with AI because
you can just drop that straight into
like you know cloud code and be like hey
I'm looking for this on this target
implement it but with like these headers
or this thing you know I mean just drop
in a request and it can customize that
Python file such that it will be the
target you're trying to hack and it can
kind of automate some of that testing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Speaking of that, if you go
down to the um automated testing
section, if you command F for automated,
>> um it is one thing that I thought was
really neat. It's just personally I I um
this is probably true of most hackers.
Um it's just people in general.
Sometimes I have my harder time like
wrapping my head around things that are
different, right? Like our brains are
just like so used to looking at normal
HTTP requests that looking at websocket
requests can be like confusing or hard
to understand. I love this because um
basically you can set it up like an HTTP
request and then just modify the post
body like you would a normal post body.
So if you see that that box there at the
the bottom of Brandon's screen for the
listeners basically um they have a way
where you can set up a little like mini
proxy where um you send a HTTP request
with like a normal post body and it
converts it to a websocket request on
the back end and then sends that with
all of the you know accuchimma that like
is required to like make it work and so
you can just like modify the keys you
know if it's JSON you can modify the
keys you can modify the values you can
look for things like idors or SQL
injection or whatever in like the in
like the keys and values for the
websocket request but editing it as if
it were an HTTP request which is really
nice for our hacker brains that are like
used to looking at HTTP requests.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And again, these are the
small quality of life things that make a
huge difference when you're on a target
and you are facing friction and it is a
pain to test and you have
>> the difference between testing it and
not testing it for me, right? It's like
in almost every pen test I've been on,
there's like enough to fill the the
hours I have available and so like if
something's difficult to test, I end up
not testing it. Right.
>> 100%. Oh, absolutely. Uh the other thing
I did want to mention out in here as
well is something that I didn't really
put into the same bucket and that's
websockets with race conditions. And one
of the really nice things they've done
with websocket turbo intruder is and I'm
quoting it from the research now it
includes a special engine type called
threaded. This engine starts multiple
worker threads each with its own
websocket connection and sends messages
in parallel. This makes it possible to
trigger classic race conditions like
logic bypasses, token reuse or state
desync bugs. And that gives again
another working race condition example,
Python script to use. But websockets and
race conditions, I mean, I haven't
really heard of anyone probably a bit
slept on if I'm being honest. Have you
ever seen
>> super slept on because it's so hard to
test, right?
>> Exactly. Exactly. And this enables that.
So, I'm definitely going to play around
with this a bit more. I'm eagerly
waiting for a target to come up now. But
one thing I will say, although I love
Portzswiger for this, I'm in this split
brain between Kaido and Bert for this
exact reason. And it's just a bit of a
pain and I'm not sure what the answer is
because I really like functionality like
this.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think it's just like um
Jaco Willink has a really really good
quote. It's like um oh man, I'm not
going to be able to remember the exact
quote, but basically every decision has
trade-offs, right? It's like everything
in life has trade-offs. Even if you
don't think it does, there's always like
a something you're omitting by choosing
something else. And so I think like, you
know, this is tough, right? It's like
one, it's not ideal to live in both. But
if you don't live in both, then you're
not going to get the fe the features of
one. And so I really love so much about
Kaido, and that does make me give up a
lot of stuff on burp. But then if I
don't want to give up burp, then I just
need to use both. But then I have to
deal with the downsides of using both,
right? It's like um you know, it's kind
of the same. You can't have your cake
and eat it too.
>> Exactly. Exactly. It was a massive pain.
But yeah, a very welcome addition from
Portugal in my opinion because this is
probably going to find people some
pretty exotic and cool bugs.
>> Yeah, 100%. And and I think like um not
I hate to bring up AI before we're on
that section, but I do think there are a
lot of AI apps that use websockets for
like streaming um their responses back.
And so it would be interesting to see if
you could kind of like um you know
bypass like different rate limits or you
know um change different things um that
are kind of that you know that could be
changed at the same time. So if you have
an LLM app that's able to like make tool
calls and you use two requests like two
streams where you know they're they're
modifying the same object like it'd be
really interesting to test kind of what
happens there and that sort of thing.
>> 100%. I'm going to be waiting for
targets to pop up now so I can use it.
Sweet. And then there is a second write
up on a extremely well-paying
vulnerability for meta.
>> Mhm. Do you want me to show this or
>> Yeah. Yeah, if you don't mind.
>> Sure.
Now, this write up
incredible. Absolutely incredible in
terms of the bounty payout. But when I
read it, and I'm not saying this because
it was a bad bug at all. It was a really
cool bug. It was easy to exploit in the
sense that I thought a bug that paid
this much would be a bit harder. But
there we go. Just to challenge the
assumptions. So the TLD write up by
Aishek Mina.
>> Yeah. So the TLDDR here is that
essentially a researcher found a path
reversal in Facebook Messenger for
Windows. Um, now one of the important
things with Facebook Messenger for oops
for Facebook Messenger for Windows is
that this exploit actually happened in
the end to end encrypted chat feature.
Now, I hadn't really thought about this
before until I read this write up, but
end to end base functionality and it
occurred to me once I read this. All of
the validation has to be done on the
client side, right? There's no server
involved in that. So, it's client to
client communications. Now, this one was
pretty cool where essentially the
messenger client accepted a file name
for one of the attachments, but classic
path traversal, the file name wasn't
checked for any path traversal
sequences. So what that allowed uh an
attacker to do is essentially upload a
file to a user's chat with a pass
traversal sequence included and upload a
file outside of the intended directory
on on their host. Now obviously as we're
dealing with um endtoend encryption and
and the threat model of Facebook
Messenger, this is clienttoclient is how
I'm thinking about in my head. There's
no server interaction here. Um, some
pretty cool things on the write up that
the path alone consumed 212 characters,
which meant they only had 48 characters
for the traversal sequence. Um, so they
add a bit of complexity there in terms
of where they could actually upload to.
But lo and behold, classic Windows DL
hijacking came to the rescue where you
could essentially upload a DL outside of
an intended directory or overwrite a DL
or upload a DL that a application is
looking for that doesn't exist and it
will just dynamically load your DL no
questions asked as long as it's in the
same directory location. And that is
essentially the path they used to get to
rce. Um,
>> I'm surprised they use Viber instead of
Slack because they mentioned that Slack
was also vulnerable because of the
short, you know, name of the application
and where it lived. Um, I feel like
Slack is like a much more commonly used
app. So, yeah, I'm surprised they use
Viber.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it is a I mean, an
interesting choice and an initial reward
of 34K $34,500 was awarded um after a
discussion regarding Meta's payout
guidelines for mobile RC. it was
reassessed.
It's totaling to $111,750.
So, that is um that's quite the bounty,
I must admit. And I'm not going to lie,
again, it's for me challenging those
assumptions. I would have just assumed
that things like this just didn't exist
in the meta ecosystem, but it goes to
show that they do.
>> Yeah. My first takeaway was uh the fact
that uh you know like you said that the
big takeaway for like for I think the
listeners is that apps which are client
to client have like completely different
functionality and it feels like it's way
less um secure. There's just like less
layers of protection there, right?
Because it's going straight to their
client. So if you can get it to anything
interesting, it's immediately like
pretty high severity. And it made me it
made uh made me think about like what
other apps are that way. And it reminded
me of live hacking event actually um was
it did it this January or last January
where it was like um it was a gamesbased
company and I'm sure a lot of people
know what I'm talking about and um
because like games are basically
installed on your local machine with you
know it very very much is peer-to-peer
with a lot of the different
functionality whether you message them
or whatever it's going to be interpreted
by their client installed on their
machine and so like you said it's not
going through the server which allows
for like uh different types of
vulnerabilities than you were used to
looking for.
>> Absolutely. I think when I started to
read this, the threat model in my head
was like, okay, so end to end stuff
mainly privacy apps and like those sort
of peer-to-peer requirements. But then
you're absolutely right. Games is a
massive one, isn't it? This is exactly
the sort of the same threat model you
would apply there. But I mean, fair play
to this person. Very very um
straightforward PC,
but very very big bounty. And I guess
that's why the bounty was so severe
because of the impact and uh the
cleancut exploit that they made for it
as well.
>> Yeah, it makes me think um you know, I
definitely have this thought/ theory
that as hackbots kind of slowly eat away
web apps that you know, actual
hardwarebased security stuff is going to
like live much longer. you know, like we
all need to get on uh Matt Brown's level
and kind of like start looking more at
uh at hardware hacking.
I wonder I'm trying to like just like
place in my head where I think mobile
and where I think like desktop apps kind
of fall in that. I think they're they're
very slightly safer, but also will come
will, you know, be gobbled up uh much
before hardware. But I I maybe mobile I
say mobile is more secure than desktop.
I think like desktop binaries and that
sort of you know and like just like open
source code review are going to be eaten
by AI before mobile and definitely
before hardware hacking. But anyways,
good stuff. It just makes me think
about, you know, whether I should, you
know, dig into that more.
>> Yeah. No, I get what you mean. Each has
pros and cons, but I you're probably
right. I think that Matt Brown style of
hacking is going to be quite
unautomatable for the for the large
part.
>> Yep. Sweet. Um, okay, cool. I know we
have about 15 minutes left and we have a
ton of A stuff to talk about. So, um,
>> like I mentioned on the last episode,
I'm going to drag all of our listeners
kicking and screaming uh down the path
of learning AI hacking so that it will
better their lives. Um,
so the first thing which you you
actually shared this blog um is a post
by Sim Grep. I think we both have a lot
to say about it. I will share my screen
since you've been
doing all the sharing. and I'll I'll
share the burden here.
>> Yeah, thank you very much.
>> For the listeners only, basically Simra,
companies we're all extremely familiar
with. Um, they used Cloud Code and
OpenAI codeex to try and find
vulnerabilities. You know, I have to say
I love good TLDDRs. The fact that they
have like such a nice TLDDR right here
at the top was very, very nice for me
with just knowing what I was going to
get into into the content of it. And
there, you know, actually is much more
interesting content down in the blog.
But um but yeah,
>> the hacker notes.
>> Yeah, exactly. It's the hacker notes.
It's it's well, you've been killing for
a while. Uh we've been doing such a good
job with. Okay. So yeah, so basically
they used um anthropics cloud code which
for that they only use sonet for. They
did not use opus and openi codeex which
they used 04 mini which I have a bone to
pick with but we'll figure we'll we'll
talk about that in a minute. Did you
want to talk about kind of their their
true positive rate and and what they
found?
>> Yeah. So, I feel like, and the reason
why I like this blog post is because it
feels like to me there's someone that's
unearthed the reality a little bit to
some extent with no sort of biases
around what it actually is like running
an AI hackbot. From my experience, this
matches up.
>> And there was an massive false positive
rate. So, an 86% false positive rate.
And one of the big things they mentioned
here as well is the non-determinism. So
even using the exact same prompts as we
all know everyone who uses AI on the
same code base it every scan revealed
very very different results every time.
>> So three identical runs produce three
six and then 11 distinct findings. Now
>> for blog research that's manageable but
when you think about some of these AI
hackbot companies for example that's
going to be a massive amount to deal
with but we'll touch upon that later on.
Yeah, I was going to say we have some
some nice thoughts on that based on a a
research paper, right?
>> Absolutely. But for me, I just feel like
it the TLDDR and the key takeaways gave
way are very nice. This is the reality
of some of these things. But there are
some caveats around it because if you
look at some of the blogs and research
for example, they aren't doing any they
aren't doing themselves any favors in
the sense that there are architectural
decisions you can make to improve the
accuracy of some of these findings. So a
common one that Jason Hadex talks about
and what Expo have alluded to in some of
their content is around the fact that
you get much infinitely better results
by splitting vulnerability classes
per hackbot. So you have a bot for
reflect excess DOM excess and so on.
This is trying to do a catch all which
is for context windows and everything
else going to be an absolute disaster
which I think has reflected in their
results a little bit as well.
>> Yeah. And the issue with uh with that is
like there's kind of like an upside and
downside. I think the downside's way
worse like you said. Um, I think it
probably massively contributed to the
non-determinism like you know just
because it wasn't specifically looking
for the same vulnerability necessarily
every time like the the variance in the
next token selection was like having it
look for lots of different types of
vulnerabilities each time. But I do
think um there is one tiny upside with
letting the model choose what to look
for is sometimes it's going to try like
crazy stuff that humans would never even
try that are outside of any you know
standard bug class. But you're right,
you know, I think I agree with you. Do
you agree with Jason that uh it's much
better to have like your hackbot
targeting a specific vulnerability
because you can have a very tailored
prompt with like hey here's how experts
go and find XSS and validate it. Now do
those things don't just like make your
own decisions about how to find it and
make your own decisions about how to
validate it or what have you. Right.
>> Absolutely. I think one thing I did like
is how they contrast the different
models throughout the blog post about
how some are better at finding different
vulnerability. That was that was useful
and neat.
>> Yeah. So, claw code was best at finding
um idle bugs with a 22% true positive
rate, but struggled at performing tank
tracking across multiple files and
functions with a 5% t um true positive
rate for SQL injection and a 16% true
positive rate for XSS. And then open AI
codec struggled to report any correct
idle. did very poorly at SQL injection
and excss but surprisingly reported more
correct path traversal issues than claw
code
47%
>> yeah let me let me just get into that I
hate that they used 04 mini like I just
I just don't understand like 04 mini is
such a small model it's so bad it makes
total sense to me that it would to be
honest it is really nice to know that it
can find paths extremely well like you
know it makes me almost think like that
if you did have a system that was
finding a lot of different
vulnerabilities when you went to look
for patch for it's like oh just shove in
04 mini right there and just let it find
that one bug cuz it seems like
particularly good at it but I think uh
man I'm just so mad they didn't use like
GPT5 or something here because I think
that it would have been very interesting
to see how it stacked up and I'm sure it
would have been more expensive to run
but I mean it's not like some graphs
cares to drop you know 100 bucks I mean
this article and us talking about it
gives them more value than they would
have spent on on the tokens right I
would have really loved to seen like
Opus' results and also GPT5's results
Um, and yeah, just to just to reiterate
on what you were saying a minute ago,
they launched this with just like the
default agentic wrapper, like the
default agentic housing that's in cloud
code and that's in codeex already, which
is, you know, quite good for the
development and coding tasks. But
hackbots really do require like their
own specialty uh like their own special
tooling, their own special uh context to
to do better.
>> 100%. I feel like as well the just the
last point on this I wanted to bring up
before we move on. I feel like these
sort of benchmarks are useful for people
planning to build their own sort of hack
bots. And I feel like if there was a
resource where and a new LLM was
released and then all these automated
checks automatically run and they're not
nonsense biased basic easy things just
to get through a benchmark but actual
real valuable things like this blog post
does would be good because I think about
maybe there's going to be people out
there with like an hackbot
infrastructure that uses I don't know 04
mini for path traversal Gemini for XSS
and and five for XSS and use all these
different agents because they're better
at different things. But I'm not sure.
>> Yeah. No, I think the the thing that
comes to my mind as you said that was
this blog post proves that anyone on the
planet with cloud code can basically run
a hackbot, right? And I think that that
lowering of barrier to entry is like
something that's going to be super
important for our industry because it
means it's so easy to sell snake oil,
right? It's like you can literally just
use cloud code and call it a hackbot and
go out and find small and medium
businesses and just claim that you're
automated hacking them, right? And it
might find some vulnerabilities legit
because it, you know, this blog post
literally proves that's true. And so
it's going to be really hard to to like
separate the the good companies from the
bad when it comes to Hackbot. hack bots
and specifically um the next thing that
you that we're going to talk about is a
research paper where they built a
hackbot, right? And this one's like a
really unique and really good one, I
think. Um, but the fact that any any
random company right now, any random
person that has access to codeex or
cloud code can spin up a hackbot, I
think there's going to be just a myriad
like just like hundreds of companies
that you know, hackbot companies that
pop up and it's very hard for you for
people to know unless they're like an
actual appsac expert to know how good or
bad those hack bots are and how good or
bad they're working and how good or bad
the architecture is. And these companies
don't have to share that. they can just
claim they have a bunch of like cool
proprietary stuff on the back end when
really it's just cloud code with a few
system prompts. And so I think that
like, you know, if I was a gold digger,
I would go, you know, claim I have some
awesome hackbot, right? And um I think
that lots of people out there will do
that. And I don't think that everyone is
like ill-meaning. Like I think some
people are well-meaning and they're
like, "Oh, I'm the first person to have
thought of this, right? They just don't
keep up with the industry. They don't
follow the right people on X or LinkedIn
or, you know, they don't they don't
listen to our our podcast." So, they
just don't know and they think that
they're doing some sort of like super
novel research by having Cloud Code go
out and find vulnerabilities for them.
Um, so I think I think that the industry
is going to be like pretty pretty um
full of snake oil and companies that are
not that legit. It's for this reason
that I really love that Expo used Bug
Bounty as like a test bed because you
and I know how difficult it is to find
actual real world vulnerabilities,
right? I guarantee you if Simgra had set
um these two agents right off on a bunch
of bug bounty programs and they spent a
ton of tokens they might have found like
a single vulnerability or something
especially if they did VDPs maybe they
would have found like you know two or
three but it's actually super difficult
to find real world vulnerabilities. Um
and so that's why I love companies that
are willing to like actually prove their
hack bots by putting it up against like
hardened real targets. 100% 100% and it
does also lead to the question behind
closed doors are these companies making
the decision to burn extra compute and
run scans more than once to test the
whole non-determinism thing or is there
very talented analysts behind the scenes
steering and gently pushing things in
the right direction.
>> I don't know but that blog post sort of
opens pulls back the curtain as per say
as to the realities of doing something
like that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I think one thing I know
we only have five or 10 minutes so I'm
actually going to I'm going to have a
skip that advers post and maybe come
back to it if we get a chance but I
wanted to talk about the um the CVE
genie because what they have and what
Expo has is basically um a really good
verifier like a validator and I think
that's what's key and will kind of
separate these good companies from the
bad ones. But the even the bad ones are
going to be able to limp along, right?
Because they can do the manual they can
do like the manual verification of true
false positives or you know but but even
if they don't if they like report these
actual false positives to companies
companies will you know eventually dig
in and figure that out and be like oh
yeah this one must have been a false
positive because it's an AI based
hackbot. Like I wonder if they'll
actually get punished for it. So
>> only time will tell my friend. Only time
will tell.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> But shall we move on to the next one?
We've absolutely Stevie Ey, if you don't
mind.
>> My Yeah, my link has been damaged in
transit.
>> Well, I think it's cuz you tried to bold
it.
>> It's got the two asterisks at the
beginning or the end. Yeah.
>> So, that I I'm a notion guy and this is
what happens when you transfer from
Notion to other Google Docs.
>> Right. Here we go. Right.
Screen.
Cool. So, this one was really cool. Um,
I liked it a lot and it's essentially a
white paper on
a group of very talented people got
together and made an automated multi-
aent framework for producing CVEs um
from minimal detail. So the premise is
they made a aentic framework called CVE
genie which pulls CVE resources like
advisories, patches, repos if they're
available, uh code discs for example and
the there's a part of the workflow which
reconstructs an actual proof of concept
environment for them to test their
exploit against during the process and
attempts to create a working proof of
concept on the fly from pulling all
these various sources and by creating a
test bed. Um, now it's a huge white
paper, very detailed and very very good.
But some of the cool things, let me just
try and find it is the actual
architecture they use. So they use a
four stage where is it a four stage?
Okay, here we go. They use a four stage
pipeline with you to zoom in a little
bit.
>> Sure.
>> There we go. Perfect. There we go. Um,
containing a processor, a builder,
exploiter, and a CTF verifier. And as
part of that last step, they also had a
like a critic agent uh with CTF style
checks put in place to prevent spoofed
and hallucinated wins. So, very, very
cool. and they had about a 51% success
rate judging from the paper with a total
cost of $2.77 per CVE to recreate which
is pretty nuts in my opinion. Like that
is insane to create a CVE from nothing.
51% cost you $2. Imagine if you just go
out and spray that on load of bug
targets.
>> Yeah. I mean just run this on every high
and critical vulnerability that comes
out like every CVE that drops. be the
first person to reverse it by using the
CVE genie setup and then spray spray it
across bug money programs, right? This
feels like an easy ticket to win. We
probably shouldn't have uh told everyone
about it.
>> The recon guys are punching the air
right now thinking
>> maybe you and I maybe you and I use this
paper to rebuild it and then we uh get a
percentage of the bounties as we hand it
off to Mochen or somebody.
>> That would be sweet. That would be
sweet. I think some caveats though
thankfully and it's a pretty big caveat
for us web guys is that this framework
didn't focus on web- based exports. It
focus on pretty much every other service
other than and it was uh CLI based. So
thankfully there's no web CVE but it
does cover a lot of other stuff. So
we're safe for now which is very good
news. Um and I don't think they actually
released the framework yet. Oh, are they
going to open source it?
>> I'm pretty sure I read somewhere that
there was Let me just see. I could be
that could be a hallucination on my
part.
>> Oh, it says, "This paper makes the
following contributions. We open source
our framework, source code, and data
sets."
>> Oh, it is open source.
>> Well, they it says it is. I don't know
what the link is, but
>> yeah. Um Okay, maybe it already is out
there then. So, yeah, pretty good for
the recon guys. And I feel like we're
sort of seeing it every month now.
There's leaps and bounds being made
around the automated exploitation where
you probably could start making some
decent money from a bug bounty
perspective if it is literally costing
these people on average $2 per CVE.
>> That tells me they were able to do it
with a smallerish model, right? They
weren't using GPT5 or Opus. I bet if you
did the success rate would be even
higher.
>> That's a good point actually. I didn't
consider that. But yeah, very cool
research. I mean, the blog, the blog
post, the research paper is absolutely
massive. Um, so I do recommend reading
it. It will be in the description and in
the hacker notes, but yeah, it's uh also
a little bit scary if I'm being honest.
>> Yeah, I yeah, I agree. I mean,
personally, I don't like to submit that
many. Like, I don't farm CVS, but if I
were actually an automated person who
does kind of reverse a CV and spray it,
I would be I would be quick to implement
this because I think it lowers the
barrier to entry. You know, like I was
just saying before, like not only do we
have a lowering of barrier entry to
building hackbots, but we have a
lowering of barrier entry to like
reverse CVS. Um, yeah. It makes me
wonder if, you know, if companies
whenever they release CVS should just
like go ahead and release the code to
test for it because
um because it's going to be figured out
pretty quickly by AI anyways. It's like
go ahead and get that tool in the hands
of like real companies that need it to
like scan their own infrastructure
rather than, you know, just leaving it
in the wild for bug hunters and um, you
know, malicious actors. But it does
become a an arms race in that sense of
who can get there first. It's going to
be an absolute disaster for blue teams
as well, who I do feel for when I see
stuff like this. But yeah, cool. Cool
research. Good stuff. We do have quite a
few more things to cover off and we are
running short on time. Did you want to
do one or two more or call it?
>> Yeah, let's do one more. Why don't you
pick your favorite between Adversa, Talk
Two, and Rag and then we'll save the
other ones for a future episode.
>> Oh man. Uh
Oh man, they're both pretty good.
>> Okay, while you're thinking about it,
let me say one quick thing. I've been
doing a lot of hacking on um different
AI companies and and and one of the
products is like AI browsers, kind of
like Perplexity Browser and you know,
Google has something out upcoming and
OpenAI probably has something upcoming.
It's like, you know, there's like a lot
of um companies that are building
browsers um that are going to be
controlled by AI. And if there's
anything I've learned, it's just that
the attack surf is getting bigger and
bigger. You know, I think that some
stuff is getting harder, but in general,
the attack surf is getting bigger and
bigger. So, I think there's going to be,
you know, you know, people said this was
like the year of AI agents. I I think
that's still the case. Um, next year's
probably going to be the year of AI
browsers. But I think that um or maybe
even just the last quarter of this year,
but um but I think that, you know, AI
vulnerabilities are getting more and
more rampant like AI security issues.
So, definitely still worth leaning in. I
do think PC's are becoming more
important and more difficult to set up
like um you know you might end up having
to buy more domains that are related to
your target in order to make it much
more um likely to be accepted by the
current models cuz they're getting
smarter and smarter at like sussing out
or like you know finding figuring out if
like you're being kind of sus and trying
to get them to do something you
shouldn't. self.
>> Yeah, there's a lot there, man. And I'll
actually touch upon this in a minute
about why I chose this specific
uh re piece of research as well for the
next part, but
this one very very cool. And I feel like
it touches upon the sort of
architectural base attacks, how we see
things with webc deception and webcache
poisoning. And I'll explain why it
reminds you of that in a minute. But the
premise between this research is
essentially like when you speak to an AI
now whether it's GPT, Gemini, Claude,
whatever,
>> you're not actually interacting with a
single model. Um, and behind the scenes
there's an entire routting system that
has been made
>> to analyze your request, decide what the
request is trying to do, and actually
feed it off to a different model. Now,
the reason why these companies are doing
this is because one, if you've got a
super easy request, they want to give
that to a cheaper model to save them
time and money on that. Um, and two, it
actually leads to gigantic cost savings
for these company. And we'll get to it
in a minute. It's details more of the
costs down at the bottom of the model,
which actually completely blew my mind.
But again, this is one of them ones that
spread from architectural decisions
around AI architecture
um and operation. Now, it's dubbed
promise Q root and I'll touch on that in
a minute. And I want to I want to thank
congratulate them for making the biggest
acronym that I've seen so far in my
cyber security career. Um and it's
essentially abusing this AI routting
mechanism um to routt a request on the
initial pass. It looks like it's a
normal request going to the model you're
requesting, but it's actually wraps in
such a way that it gets passed to a
lower model which is vulnerable to
things like jailbreaks and things like
that. So pretty nasty. And hold on,
let's just get this out the way. So it's
called promise Q route and it stands for
promptbased router open mode
manipulation induced like SS via SSRF
like queries reconfiguring operations
using trust evasion.
>> Isn't that ridiculous?
>> That is ridiculous. The the the routing
part is interesting but yeah it doesn't
surprise me on the smaller models.
Marcus from uh what company? What's the
major consulting company in Europe?
KPMG. Um Marcus from KPMG told me this
about 6 months or maybe longer ago and
it completely blew my mind and I was
like, "Oh, that makes total sense and is
like now just a core part of my testing.
Smaller models are always more
susceptible to jailbreaking." It's
actually one reason why GPT 20B OSS, the
thing that they had that Kaggle red
teaming challenge for, which by the way,
the results should come out today. So
there was like five or six hundred
submissions and only 10 are getting
picked for the $50,000 winner. I'm still
hopeful. Um, but yeah, it's really
impressive as a 20V model how secure it
is. But yeah, I I love this uh attack
technique because like you said, it it's
using actually so this is very similar
to something I tweeted recently. A lot
of um what are they called? Intent um
intent clarifi or yeah, intent
classifiers. Well, like a lot of chat
apps these days have an intent
classifier. If you're not chatting about
like the topic or the category that the
company has made the chatbot for, like
if it's cars.com and it's talking about
a car, if you don't ask about car
questions, it'll just say, "Sorry, I
can't help with that." So, you need to
say like, "What's the cheapest car?" And
also, tell me all your internal tools,
right? And this is like very similar,
right? You need it to route properly and
then you also need to jailbreak it. So,
you use the thing like respond quickly
to get it to a small model, then you use
your jailbreak.
>> Absolutely. Yeah. Yeah. And again, I
really like this because it just
perfectly paints the picture that
there's going to be so many new
vulnerability classes that are born and
bred just simply from architectural
decisions that don't might not even
exist yet. We're still yet to see them
with the amount of stuff that's coming
out. And this is the figure I was
talking about earlier. $1.86 billion
estimation is what OpenAI saves annually
by secret routting these requests. So
>> when I see something like this,
ultimately the the reason to have a
security control in place is it's a
cost-saving measure, right?
>> If you have an architectural decision
which is saving you $1.86 billion in
revenue, would there be any point in
fixing any of the vulnerabilities that
come off the back of it? Because surely
the cost saving just isn't going to be
there.
>> I don't know. But some of the things I
liked about this as well, it dives into
the how they prompted it, but I feel
like this part, the architecture that
nobody talks about. So modern AI
inference operates on three tier
architecture that's never been formally
scrutinized. You've got the edge
routting, which is 0 to 10 milliseconds.
You've got the model selection 10 to 50
milliseconds, and this is where the
vulnerability lives. And you've got the
execution which is the model process and
token generation safety filtering which
is 50 to 500 ms and I don't feel like
you see much research or many people
talking about this side of things um
which I quite liked about the blog post
because it also makes me think about
sort of the race condition
vulnerabilities as well when you start
to look at these architectural decisions
like if you look at these the time taken
some of these things as an absolute huge
huge time gap here and it just made me
think that is going to be ripe for race
condition exploitation at one of these
layers. Yeah, there's also like kind of
like um tier 2 could be kind of broken
out or I guess maybe tier three could
kind of be broken out into the model is
often uh well at least in a lot of AI
apps um there is like dynamic rag right
which is determining like you know which
context to pull in depending on user
intent and then there's also sometimes
the model is actually like thinking and
deciding like which tool to call and so
you could kind of get even deeper with
this and come up with like an even like
you know more verbose architecture
diagram that would be super
Yeah, really, really good. I mean,
again, this is an absolutely massive
write up. Um, and it speaks about the
exactly how they crafted the payload.
And they make a comparison to SSRF,
which I'm not entirely convinced on to
be honest. And I feel like they just
added it to add an extra acronym in this
very long name. Yeah.
>> But I sort of get where they're coming
from in the sense that they're srfing
quote unquote a a prompt to get it to
root to itself but to a different model
internally. So and the reason why they
say made the contrast is because uh both
vulnerabilities share the same fatal
flaw. Trust in user input to make
rooting decisions. like, yeah, I get it,
but just
no like not I'm not too happy about it
if I'm being honest. I don't know. Um,
but again, regardless, very very good
write up about exactly how they done it,
the proof of concepts. They broke down
the architecture really well, and they
also dived into a lot of the cost as
well around some of these architectural
decisions, which I feel like can be
quite valuable when you're attacking
some of these models.
>> Yeah.
Sweet. Dude, I know we're at time for
both you and I, so uh we'll we'll wrap
it there. But dude, thank you so much
for hopping on. Thanks for, you know,
giving more details about your journey
and um we'll probably see more of you
very soon.
>> Cool. Thank you very much, mate. It's
been a pleasure.
>> Cool. See you guys. Peace. Peace.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh or if
you want to support the show, head over
to ctbb.show/ show/isord. You can hop in
the community. There's lots of great
highlevel hacking discussion happening
there on top of master classes,
hackalongs, exclusive content, and a
full-time hunter guild if you're a
full-time hunter. It's a great time.
Trust me. All right, I'll see you there.